Simone Marra

Iot / Web / Mobile Developer



Summary

Passionate for electronics, embedded firmware programmer, Mobile/Web development.

Excellent teamwork attitude, experienced customer support and "step-by-step/learn by examples" online tutorials.

Skills

Firmware developer

C firmware developer for Microcontrollers (ARM, PIC, Xmos, etc...)

TCP/IP Stack + TLS (mbedTLS)

Wi-Fi, Ethernet and GPRS/3G Connectivity

IOT, HTTPS, MQTT, Microsoft Azure IOTHUB

Bluetooth LE

Embedded Linux (openwrt, raspberry)

Web developer

Backend:

- Nodejs
- .NETCore (C#)

Frontend:

- Angular
- Bootstrap

Mobile developer

Xamarin Forms

Other skills

Scrum planning Tasks

Git/Mercurial repository

Wiki / Markdown / Doxygen Documentation

Personal info

Born November the 4th, 1983.

Since child I was introduced to electronics, music and diy by my family.

Now I am passing on all my knowledge and passions to my daughter, trying to raise a human being better than me, along with my wife.

Education

3-years Electronics Engineering

La Sapienza University, Roma, Italia

Work experience

Developer

Trackting

IoT-enabled Smart Alarms and Trackers

- Firmware developer
- Arduino-Compatible (Cortex-M0 secondary microcontroller development)
- Linux Embedded connected devices
 - o OpenWRT
 - o Raspberry Pi with both Raspian and Windows IOT-Core systems
- Azure
 - IotHub cloud communication
 - o App Service Plan Deployment
- Mobile App
 - Ionic framework development (multi-platform Android, iOS, Windows)
 - Xamarin.Forms development (multi-platform Map-based Android, iOS and Windows app)
- Backend development
 - o ASP.NET Core
 - $\circ \ Node.JS$
- Angular front-end development

Developer of Hearing aid helper systems

2008 - 2012

Udito Farm

- Audiometer Hardware design
- Audiometer Firmware development
- Audiometer Control Windows-based GUI
- Embedded Linux (OMAP3530-based) video-recording system
- Interactive DVD for hearing-aid support (dvd-reader multimedia content)

Firmware developer & documentation

2011 - 2018

Openpicus

Firmware developer, documentation, customer support.

IP (Wi-fi Ethernet and GSM/GPRS) connected devices using Flyport-module platform (microchip tcp/ip stack, self-made GSM at-commands parser, freeRTOS)

- Flyport Wifi module libraries
- Flyport Ethernet framework development
- Flyport GPRS framework development
- Wiki & Manuals
- Customer support

- C# Windows IDE development
- MQTT IOT platform for rapid prototyping (cloud based, no programming skills needed, online configure and use expansion devices)

Custom Hardware & Firmware developer

2012 - 2013

Varone Impianti Pneumatici (Industrial pneumatic money transfer systems)

- Custom HW development with rs-485 bus and motor control
- Firmware development
- C#-WPF Windows based control software & PostgreSQL database data storage
- IR reflection presence sensor

DSP HW/SW developer

2014 - Present

UditoFarmPiù-Active-INAIL

Active control noise system based on XMOS platform.

- Custom HW development
- DSP-routines firmware development

Firmware developer

2015 - 2016

Smartables

Bluetooth Smart (BLE, Low energy) & ARM wearable devices

- CSR BLE firmware development
- Nordic nRF51 BLE firmware development
- Freescale Kinetis firmware development

Developer

2016 - Present

Iomote

Microsoft Azure IoT-enabled Devices, Iot-services

- ARM Cortex IOT connected devices
 - o Ethernet
 - o Wi-Fi
 - o GPRS/3G
 - GPS
- Arduino-Compatible (Cortex-M0 secondary microcontroller development)
- Linux Embedded connected devices
 - o OpenWRT
 - o Raspberry Pi with both Raspian and Windows IOT-Core systems
- Azure
 - IotHub cloud communication
 - App Service Plan Deployment
- Mobile App
 - Ionic framework development (multi-platform Android, iOS, Windows)
 - Xamarin.Forms development (multi-platform Map-based Android, iOS and Windows app)
- Backend development
 - o ASP.NET Core
 - o Node.JS

• Angular front-end development

Created with 🔽 VisualCV